Guide to the Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting (FAIR) Records TAM.282
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting (FAIR) Records
1983-1993
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Fairness & Accuracy in Reporting (Organization)
TAM.282
0.75 Linear Feet (1 box)
Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting (FAIR) is a progressive media watch organization founded in 1986 by journalist Jeff Cohen. FAIR publishes Extra!, a magazine of media criticism, and produces Counterspin, a radio news program. It is active against censorship, and advocates for diversity, and the break up of the dominant media conglomerates. The collection includes correspondence (mostly of Jeff Cohen), internal documents, and back issues of publications.
Box 1
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting (FAIR) in 1994. The accession number associated with this collection is 1994.005.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically.
Historical/Biographical Note
Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting (FAIR), a progressive media watch organization that works with journalists and activists, was founded in 1986 by journalist Jeff Cohen. FAIR publishes Extra!, a magazine of media criticism, and produces Counterspin, a radio news program. FAIR conducts media research, produces reports (notably through its Womens' Desk and Racism Watch Desk units), opposes censorship, and advocates for greater diversity and representation of minority viewpoints. FAIR believes that structural reform is ultimately needed to break up the dominant media conglomerates, to establish independent public broadcasting, and to promote strong non-profit sources of information.
Custodial History
The archived website was migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The link to California Digital Library was removed in October 2017.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains correspondence (mostly that of Jeff Cohen), internal documents, reports and studies, editorial material pertaining to Extra!, back issues (1992) of Counterspin: A Memo on Campaign Coverage from FAIR, published and unpublished writings by Jeff Cohen and others, a file on FAIR's Los Angeles chapter, and another on related organizations.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Reports.; Writings (document genre); Mass media criticism |z United States.; Correspondence.; Fairness & Accuracy in Reporting (Organization); Cohen, Jeff, 1951-
- Records
  - Cohen, Jeff: Writings, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: ABC, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: PBS, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Counterspin: A Memo on Campaign Coverage from FAIR, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Documents, Ephemera, Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Documents, Ephemera, Clippings, 1986-1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Extra! (Editorial Material), 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Faces of War(Documentary on Central America), 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - FAIR: Los Angeles Chapter, 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Founding of FAIR / Initial Activities, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Related Organizations, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Report: Are You on the Nightline Guest List?, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Report: Lost in the Margins: Labor & the Media, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Report (to FAIR): Network Television & Newspaper Coverage of the Environment Since Earth Day 1990, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Report: Public Television "Prime Time": Public Affairs Programming, Political Diversity, & the Conservative Critique of Public Television, by David Croteau, et al, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Safire, William" - by Robert Ranflet, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Women & Media Activism Kit, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Archived Website, Oct 2, 2007-ongoing
  Scope and Content Note
  FAIR (Fairness & Accuracy in Reporting), a national media watch group, has been offering criticism of media bias and censorship since 1986. FAIR advocates greater diversity in the press, structural reform in the media, and works to expose neglected news stories. FAIR publishes Extra!, a magazine of media criticism, and produces the weekly radio program CounterSpin. In addition, they have a listserv through which they distribute regular action alerts to their international network of activists.